Hi there, I'm Walith, your instructor for this course on Java.
More on me later.
You might be wondering, why did I make a course on Java in the year 2026?
Well, Java is still used extensively across the industry, and it's still powering some of
the most important systems in the world, and those reasons are enough for you to start
to get a solid understanding of the most rewarding programming language of the past almost
30 years.
Now on to me.
I've spent over 16 years working across software engineering and training roles, and
the past few years, I've had the privilege of training thousands of engineers across different
countries, backgrounds, and skill levels.
Along the way, I've learned people don't struggle because they're not smart enough.
They struggle because the fundamentals were not explained, or they were explained too fast,
too vaguely, or too much as you knowledge.
This course here is designed to fix that.
I would just show you the Java syntax, I'll explain why it exists, went to use it, and
how real developers actually think when writing code.
You will see real examples like debugging and even mistakes made of purpose, because that's
how real learning happens.
Across this course, I would be keeping you updated with the latest changes in different
Java versions, and what those changes brought to the table.
I'll also break model tooling into the mix, including AI coding assistance.
Now, wait a minute.
Did I say AI?
Yes, because how could I make a course in 2026 without at least mentioning artificial
intelligence?
And you will learn to use AI not as a replacement for learning, but to speed up your workflow.
So if you're ready to learn Java confidently, and which makes you interested, ready to
use Java the modern way, let's get started.